Guide to the Russian lesbian, gay, and AIDS-related publications and ephemera,1992-1997.
Russian Lesbian, Gay, and AIDS-related Publications and Ephemera, 1992-1997
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Russian lesbian, gay, and AIDS-related publications and ephemera, 1992-1997.
7694
1 c.f. plus 1 oversize folder
Kevin Lamb
Printed materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Material collected in Moscow and St. Petersburg, Russia, during the 1996-97 academic year, while Lamb worked for Aesop, a Moscow AIDS prevention organiation, running their gay and bisexual men's outreach program. Some material was purchased at bookstores and erotic boutiques, and some was picked up in bars and clubs.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Material collected in Moscow and St. Petersburg, Russia, during the 1996-97 academic year, while Lamb worked for Aesop, a Moscow AIDS prevention organiation, running their gay and bisexual men's outreach program. Some material was purchased at bookstores and erotic boutiques, and some was picked up in bars and clubs.
Included are 14 books of poetry and fiction with gay themes either written in or translated into Russian, including the first Russian translation of James Baldwin's Giovanni's Room. These are cataloged separately.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Lamb, Kevin.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Collecting Program: Human Sexuality Collection.
CONTAINER LIST
- Homosexuality- General, 1991-1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Foreign Press- Russian Gay Life, 1990, 1992-1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Gay culture/literature/language, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Transexuality- Queer "other", 1991-1994, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- HIV/AIDS in Russia, 1987, 1990's (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Ephemera: Club brochures, invitations, promos, etc., 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Gay + Lesbian film festival (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Index on censorship- "Gay's the Word in Moscow" (Box 1, Folder 8)
- V. Kozlovskii- "The Argot of Russian Homosexual Sebculture" (Box 1, Folder 9)
- A. Shchuplov- "Slang Scoop" (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Moscow Lesbian Periodical no. 4 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- The Triangle Center (Box 1, Folder 12)
- The Names Fund, info plus (Box 1, Folder 13)
- AIDS Information Connection (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Aesop (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Gender Doc, The Mirror (Box 1, Folder 16)
- 10 to 1 (amateur journal) (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Awakening (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Tema (complete set) [REMOVED FROM COLLETION NOW CATALOGGED SEPERATLEY] (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Tema International (Box 1, Folder 20)
- 1/10 #2-14 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- 1/10 #15-22 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Argot (illustrated) (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Dimka (erotic magazine) (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Risk (to dissent) (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Risk (literary) (Box 1, Folder 26)
- You (illustrated) (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Uranus (erotic magazine) (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Little Partner, ed. by Misha Anikeev (Box 1, Folder 29)
- AIDS, Sex, Health- St. Petersburg AIDS organization (Box 1, Folder 30)
- St. Petersburg literary/erotic periodical- Erotica in Russian Literature from Barkov to the Present (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Impulse, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Gay Glory!, Gay literary journal in St. Petersburg, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Little Man (illustrated) (Box 1, Folder 34)
- My Journal for the Few 1995 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- All Colors of the Rainbow- subscription acquaintance service (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Chance (gay newspaper), 1992 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Gay Dialog, Dialog Plus, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Queer Imaginings: The Unauthorized Reign of Russia's Queeniest of Queens, by K. Lamb, 1998 (Box 1)
- "I Have AIDS, Hug Me, I'm Not Infectious" poster (Folder 1)
  ad for the AIDS Hotline for Kids, Tiburon, California, 1987
- HIV/AIDS information poster, Moscow, n.d. (Folder 1)
- Poster for a Queen concert in Moscow, [1991?] (Folder 1)